<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../src-generated/schemas/fhir-single.xsd" lang="en">
  <a name="scope"></a>
  <p>
    This is a FHIR Implementation guide for HIV Case Reporting developed as part of the <a
      href="https://www.notion.so/jembi/What-is-DISI-646e781e568e4f9db5ca4619f99334d5">DISI initiative</a>.
  </p>

  <blockquote class="stu-note">
    <strong>This documentation and set of artefacts are still undergoing development.</strong>
    This content is only for demonstrative purposes.
  </blockquote>

  <p></p>
  <a name="navigation"> </a>
  <p>The top menu allows quick navigation to the different sections, and a <a href="toc.html">Table of Contents</a> is
    provided with the entire content of this Implementation Guide. (Be aware that some pages have multiple tabs).</p>

  <a name="introduction"></a>
  <h3>Introduction</h3>
  <p>This FHIR IG describes how and submit HIV case reports to a central server conforming to the DISI architecture. The
    profiles created in this IG correspond to the minumum data set defined for the DISI architecture. This minimum data
    set may be <a
      href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1K22pfrMVlFvgm3AsTMX5HggqbFnVOeLF/edit#gid=2067500832">found
      here</a>.</p>
  <p>The sections that follow describe how to submit case reports and link out to the profiles resources to specify
    exactly what is required to be submitted. If an implementation require additional modifications it is suggested a
    new IG be created that used this one as a base and further specifies additional rules on the already profiles
    resources.</p>

  <a name="submitting-case-reports"></a>
  <h3>Submitting case reports</h3>
  <p>Case report may be submitted in one of three different ways:</p>
  <ul>
    <li><strong>FHIR Native (transactional)</strong> - this approach allows applications with advanced FHIR capabilities
      to submit a
      case report as a FHIR document bundle. This approach gives maximum control over how resources are created and
      referenced, however, is also more complex to implement.</li>
    <li><strong>FHIR Naive (batch)</strong> - this approach allows applications to submit case report as simply as
      possible via
      CSV even if the submitting application does not support any FHIR capabilities. It also allows for batches are case
      reports to be submitted further simplifying application functionality.</li>
    <li><strong>FHIR Aware (transactional)</strong> - this approach allows applications to submit case reports using
      FHIR but in a
      simple way by utilizing a single resource: the QuestionnaireResponse. This is much simpler to implement which
      remaining FHIR compliant.</li>
  </ul>

  <a name="fhir-bundle"></a>
  <h4>FHIR Bundle</h4>
  <p>
    When submitting as a FHIR bundle you may submit individual HIV sentinel event or a full case report with multiple
    sentinel event. The FHIR bundle must be structured as a <a href="https://www.hl7.org/fhir/documents.html"
      target="_blank">FHIR
      document</a> with a Composition resource as the first item
    in the bundle entries. The Composition resource has a section per sentinel event. Each of those section references
    the other FHIR resources (one or more) that hold the actual data relating to that sentinel event. See the profile
    for that Composition resource with links to the other profiles resources here: <a
      href="StructureDefinition-hiv-composition.html">Profiles Composition</a>
  </p>
  <p>The document is to be submitted to a <a href="https://www.hl7.org/fhir/http.html#transaction" target="_blank">FHIR
      transaction
      endpoint</a> using an HTTP POST coforming to the core FHIR specifications.</p>
  <p>A full example of a case report bundle with all sentinel event filled in can be seen <a
      href=" Bundle-HIVBundleExample.json.html">here</a>.</p>

  <a name="csv"></a>
  <h4>CSV</h4>
  <p>To allow for simple batch import of case report data may be submitted in a CSV format. A sample of the expected CSV
    format can be <a
      href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1g6rSiNgA1tuqQ4qHUyN8l6utFbvU6Pe0y_4lP8nhz6Q/edit?usp=sharing"
      target="_blank">found
      here</a>. The headers must be exactly as stipulated in this example and repeating fields are handled by joining
    values together in a single column separated by a '|' character.</p>
  <p>The CSV must be submitted using an HTTP POST with a content-type header of 'text/plain' and the raw csv text in the
    HTTP body.</p>

  <a name=" fhir-questionnaire-response"></a>
  <h4>FHIR QuestionnaireResponse (not yet implemented)</h4>
  <p>This section is not yet developed</p>

  <a name="ip"> </a>
  <h3>Intellectual Property Considerations</h3>
  <p>
    While this implementation guide and the underlying FHIR are licensed as public domain, this guide includes examples
    making use of terminologies such
    as LOINC, SNOMED CT and others which have more restrictive licensing requirements. Implementers should make
    themselves familiar with licensing and
    any other constraints of terminologies, questionnaires, and other components used as part of their implementation
    process. In some cases,
    licensing requirements may limit the systems that data captured using certain questionnaires may be shared with.
  </p>

  <a name="disclaimer"> </a>
  <h3>Disclaimer</h3>
  <p>
    The specification herewith documented is a demo working specification, and may not be used for any implementation
    purposes.
    This draft is provided without warranty of completeness or consistency, and the official publication supersedes this
    draft.
    No liability can be inferred from the use or misuse of this specification, or its consequences.
  </p>
</div>